my experience has been that if you can
show impact if you can show like a like
a pricing Matrix table that says hey you
should not be able to configure the you
know single sign on for a non-enterprise
organization and you can and it works
for like a pro level organization or
something like that and there's a little
X in the Box for pro and there's a
little you know check mark in the Box
for for business then trck of having
documentation for your product is a
reading it that's the you know and and
and if you never make documentation then
they can't call you out on
[Music]
[Applause]
it hey everyone this is techn geek here
just wanted to give a quick shout out to
our latest sponsor project Discovery now
project Discovery makes a lot of tools
that you probably know of or have even
used uh one of them is nuclei and the
latest release of nuclei is version 3.2
now 3.2 comes with a lot of really
awesome new features um two that I
really wanted to highlight here for you
are the authenticated scanning and the
advanced fuzzing support now for
authenticated scanning it used to be
that you would have to do all your
nuclei scanning against unauthenticated
end points or you'd have to add your
cookies manually all that kind of messy
no more it's all automatic you can use
existing login templates to
automatically log to your application
and then you can run all your existing
nuclei templates against an
authenticated part of the application
now to really increase your coverage uh
the other that I mentioned is Advanced
fuzzing support now nuclea had added way
back in version 2.8 the ability to fuzz
different things but now they've
expanded this comprehensively across the
board so not only can you fuzz in the
normal spots but you can fuzz within
headers you can fuzz within cookies you
can fuzz within specific parts of the
body whether that's in Json or XML or
form data and so many more things so if
you want to learn more about what came
in nuclei 3.2 go ahead and check out the
the release blog post over at nu.
gpod that's
n.p podcast
thanks you hear that
ah nothing like the sweet smell of
allergies that
is that is the sweet The Sweet Sound of
a clear nasal passage and sickness is
gone I'm I'm almost there um I'm like
90% of the way there all right well hang
in there man hang in there I'm feeling
110% back in the game after last week
having a nice restful week off so thanks
for taking over the Pod last week man
yeah of course
absolutely um we got some stuff we're
going to cover today as
usual um you've been doing some hacking
lately you want to talk a little bit
about that sure yeah I talked about it a
little bit at the beginning of last
episode but um yeah I've been um I took
a little vacation and uh I was uh I got
that that little itch again and uh I
just started I just started digging in
on some Target that I had been
interested in for a while um and I just
found a bunch of really interesting you
know sort of almost bugs and stuff and
then um I hit a bit of a stopping point
so I sent a bunch of it over to you and
then in like five minutes you started
escalating
stuff classic classic collaboration we
like we like started writing stuff up we
submitted it then we checked the scope
page and it was explicitly out of scope
so we self closed it um so yeah it's uh
just one of those things but it was it
was a good experience have you have you
followed up with that Target at all
after that day or did we did we get a a
gut punch there with the
oscope um well I think had I had to
return back to normal a little bit as
well so I think um I lost a little bit
of the momentum
so haven't returned back to the Target
yet but maybe I will I might I might I
think that there's there's some other
things for me to look at that website
was sketchy as heck dude there's a lot
of weird things going on there was there
was a lot of weird stuff I think it
happens you know sometimes and I think
it's good to put it on air on the pot as
well that you know this sort of thing
happens to more experienced bug Hunters
as well where you're just like you know
you kind of get in your flow or you're
excited to look at a Target or whatever
and you start poking at it poking what
what what did you say poke pokey pokey
poke at
it poke at it till you can't poke at it
anymore and then um and then you know
you realize something's out of scope and
you know it's just the the L's we take
along the way in bug Bounty right it it
happens it happens it's part all part of
the process you know it is indeed it is
indeed So speaking of El's um I did want
to talk a little bit about the uh the
Ambassador World Cup because every other
country besides the us is going to be
taken an L uh
no hopefully that's how was sure where
you're going with that I was like wait a
sec um no uh I just so you know the
first round of the Ambassador World Cup
has been completed and the results are
not um and when I say the Ambassador
World Cup of course I'm speaking about
the hacker one Ambassador World Cup
hacking competition where um ambassadors
from all the different countries around
the world uh and their teams are
competing in a hacking competition um
for uh what last year was an in-person
life hacking event and uh a bunch of
prizes and that sort of thing so um
pretty fun little thing uh however
something was really odd with it this
year which kind of threw me off a little
bit as a full-time Hunter Okay so we've
got 700 over 700 hackers participating
in this right it's a pretty big event
it's it's massive it's massive so just
for for scale size that's you know 15
times the normal live hacking event
right you got 50 people you know roughly
so it puts it at at a pretty decent
ratio there um
there's no dupe
window that seems a little off to me man
because like for me as a full-time
Hunter who's doing this for my
livelihood right why am I going to
expose myself so expose myself to what
is the equivalent of probably a hundred
times or or more the dupe risk and man I
have seen some absolutely gutting dupes
come through from this live hacking man
like
like people working really hard getting
what what should be 25k Plus crits
getting duped out um within and they
submitted them within you know the first
couple days of the competition yeah yeah
so I think I don't know it seems a
little off to me yeah so we have
participated
in the Ambassador World Cup before um
from the program Zone I I have um and
okay I think I don't remember how it
works and they might have changed it
this year um
but it's could be a points thing so one
thing to remember is that teams are
given points based on the severity of
bugs found I don't recall how duping
affects that and whether or not dupes
count like if you have a dupe of a crit
does that count as points even though
it's not uh Bounty no it does not it
does not so so it's like it's kind of
like a double whammy because obviously
you know if dupes counted you would be
getting some gamification of that that
whole thing but um you know it's it's no
Bounty no no points right and and I
could understand if if they wanted to
say like okay you know we we'll give you
um you know no points because whoever
gets the first submission in gets the
points but no Bounty like like I mean
across these 700 hackers so many so many
of them have spent all this time on
these targets can I can't even fathom
the amount of like hacker hours wasted
because of dupes on this right whereas
at least with the live and then here's
the other piece of this right like the
bounties aren't that inflated for the
Ambassador World Cup right so if they
were Mega inflated it's like okay well
I'm exposing myself to a little extra
risk for a little extra reward right but
the only reward in this situation is you
get to move on to the next round of the
Ambassador World Cup right yeah um and
and so I think I think for me as a
full-time Hunter it's hard for me to
justify just from a financial
perspective whether like should I be
investing time in this or not because at
the end of the day my dup risk is so
much higher and my reward is nominally
you know more so I don't know maybe I'm
off base with that that being said I did
put you know I want to say like 15 hours
or so like two days into the competition
just to kind of support my team I got a
couple triage bugs so um you know it is
what it is you know it'll it'll it'll
pan out one way or the other but I I
next and and also let me just caveat
this explanation with like I get that
it's hard for hacker one to deal with
dupes and at this scale you know when
when we're dealing with uh you know 700
hackers how how do you even in like 1400
submissions how do you even ddop across
1400 submissions um very challenging
across three targets even uh but I still
think that it strongly de incentivizes
the hacker the hacker that takes their
time and and you know time investment in
these sort of things
seriously yeah yeah it's definitely
tricky um because I don't think the
programs are asked to operate you know
really differently than you know they're
basically
still um the public programs that are
participating right so it's um it's not
like a fullon live hacking event or
anything like that it's like halfway
between so yeah I did I did appreciate
that the that the bounties for the um
for one of the targets they increased
the mediums and the lows at least which
is like okay you know that's something
and and I think increasing
mediums is an under underrated play by
programs because that really does help
put some some you know cash back in the
hacker pocket along the way especially
if you're like a a very like a chain
heavy um and like a uh a sort of a
progressive hacker like I am like I'll
get in there and I'll find a couple
mediums you know I'm looking at these
sort of medium and low severity bugs as
well as going for these bigger ones
instead of trying to put them all
together so but sometimes along the way
you're just going to run into some
mediums so it definitely helps you get
those paid out well yeah for sure and I
will say like the the the one advantage
that um there is to sort of you know
making it to that next round uh other
than you know just the fact of making it
there is that
theoretically that dup you know rate or
whatever goes down as you you know
filter down to fewer and fewer teams so
in theory it does get easier in a sense
or hard you know harder but easier like
less dupes um but more skilled teams
yeah yeah it's it's more of a hustle I
think you know in this in this first
round than it will be on the later
rounds and that's what some of the guys
in the chat were saying but um yeah you
know maybe it's it's the price you pay
and and for me you know somebody who for
me and you Joel you know people that are
are sort of austo to the live hacking
event um circuit or whatever it it may
seem as like okay well why aren we being
actually incentivized here but uh but
for you know the people that haven't had
the opportunity to participate in a live
hacking event and that's their like you
know bucket list item or whatever then
uh then you know having the opportunity
to participate in a live hacking event
is like the ultimate motivation so yeah
I can yeah have you um have you ever
seen an F1 race have what have you ever
seen an F1 race
have I ever seen oh an F1 race no I
haven't seen an F1 race okay well have
you ever seen like a clip of an F1 race
starting no no okay well maybe this
analogy will fly over you but I feel
like this is this is very much so like
the first turn in the race where uh it's
it's always turn one where just like
[__] hits the fan and all the cars just
like every because everybody's like
starting and trying to like get ahead
yeah every really tight they're trying
to like get whatever lead they can
they're all like you know inches from
each other and like uh disaster strikes
and then whoever just makes it out of
that is
immediately ahead of the pack right so
that's kind of like what's going on here
with round one of the World Cup is you
know it's turn one so everybody's uh
everybody's neck and neck and whoever
makes it through the blood bath at the
beginning will uh you know inevitably
lead the pack we'll see we'll see I
don't know where I I think last last
night uh us was in fourth place or
something like that so I think third now
actually are we at third nice I believe
soet sweet so hey you know there's
there's a chance there's a chance um
dude I don't know why like I I don't
know if it was just like the intonation
or something but it sounded like you
were saying like have you ever seen an
F1 raise like like and I I like is this
some sort of like knock knock joke or
something like that like I don't know
how I'm who's there you know like who
exactly like how am I supposed to
respond to this um all right
well moving along from that uh did you
did you get a chance to peek at this uh
no Kleine um Zoom atto yeah man uh
really interesting bug there was some
stuff in there that I was like I I don't
even know like the Google ooth thing is
that like a Zer day I don't even no you
know well I I think it depends on the
implementation you know uh Google
Google's got a bunch of little nuances
to their to their oath flow but um I
thought this one was really a really
cool example of like a really solid
client side exploit chain and and um
sort of using all these different pieces
along the way youve got a little bit of
CSP you got a little bit of cookies you
got you know um you know cookie tossing
you've got the post space xss you've got
the the cookie xss and and then chaining
it all the way through to create
something of massive impact and I was
actually thinking about eel when
whenever I was reading this because I
was like um you know I know that you
your focus has has often been a lot on
mobile and apis and that sort of thing
when you're looking at this stuff A lot
of times you're looking more at um you
know the backend stuff because that's
the the stuff you've got more exposure
to when it comes to um you know hacking
apis through the mobile front and this
is I think is just a really cool um
example of like how all of this stuff
can be applied in in front end in in in
in the browser in a full chain um so for
any of you guys that haven't read it um
it's it's super good we'll link it in
the description um I guess the tldr of
this is that there was a a cookie based
xss in Zoom that affected I love this
the the CSP feature uh for for Zoom so
apparently you could set a cookie that
would reflect a non into the
CSP and um oh okay so this was this was
a really interesting takeaway that is
also something that I I've been looking
at recently um
the way that they reflected their
content into the the header uh this or
the CSP the nons attribute for the
script thank you Joel Joel's over there
like you got it Justin
like um was was this cookie parsing
thing have you seen this like double
qued cookie parser
odity um yeah so I guess I never really
thought about it but I definitely have
seen this where cookies
right if you think about it this this um
this kind of exists in a couple
different areas I think a great example
of it is um with HTML elements actually
where you can define an HTML attribute
with within an element without quotes
with quotes with slashes you know
there's a ton of different separators
right so you could just be like input
equals value and then you could put a
space and it'll just assign value to
input or you can surround it with quotes
maybe there's special characters or
single quotes double quotes right
exactly so it's very similar kind of
thing here where I assume that um the
reasoning is maybe there's special
characters maybe there's spaces I think
technically you're supposed to URL en
code cookies uh cookie values in
entirely um but this is probably trying
to account for maybe some weird special
Edge case or just to give the option for
you to send a non URL and coded cookie
which I don't really know how that would
ever happen um but yeah yeah so you can
basically wrap your cookie values in um
in quotes or double quotes and that that
seems to allow you to basically bypass
it by like wrapping a double quote and a
single quote right exact exactly so so
yeah there's there's a lot of oddities
to the way that cookies are parsed and I
feel like it's not something that's
super looked into and we we talked about
this actually at the beginning of the
year in um the top 10 web hacking
techniques from excuse me from
2023 post because there was a some
research done and I I forget who it was
by but I've actually referenced it on a
couple podcasts since then so I think it
was probably some of the more impactful
research that was done in 2023 um for
sure about cookie parsing and like for
example you can put like cookies that
don't have any values or cookies that
don't have like some specific parts of
it right and it will sometimes the
backend server will get confused and
like smush cookie values together and
you'll be able to like cancel out
headers or other cookies you know by
setting a specific cookie so um there's
all sorts of of oddities there and the
one that they're using in this scenario
is that um if you put in you know let's
just say you set the cookie value for
this non to uh ABC double quote you know
ABC right it's going to properly figure
that out and remove the double quote and
just put put it into the nons you know
just ABC uh and then cut off everything
after that but if you do if you open the
cookie value with a double quote so
you're doing like equals double quote
and then a ABC backs slash double quote
ABC and then close it with a double
quote then it's sort of like a string
encapsulated value for that for that
cookie and um and then that value gets
reflected un un unescaped into the the
script um nons uh attribute in HTML uh
and and I think I think that this was a
very apt time for me to be reading this
right up because there was a
vulnerability that I discovered recently
that uh I was not able to exploit um and
that a lot of let's just let me see I
know what you're talking about I need to
be I need to be more vague about this
because uh yeah because it's a lot a lot
of hackers were when when are unable to
yes a lot of hackers were unable unable
to exploit this vulnerability and there
was a particular hacker uh a hacker that
you will hear you guys will hear this
write up story at some point um but a
particular hacker was able to come in
and exploit this vulnerability because
of very similar logic to this with a
double quote being placed into uh a
cookie value and being able to cut off
uh uh like the cookies that come after
this uh up until another double quote or
some other weird parsing cookie parsing
nonsense um so I I I think that this is
a really strong takeaway is like if you
get caught in a situation where your
cookie like maybe you need to do cookie
tossing and you're sending two cookies
to the server or like um there's a
cookie that isn't being reflected
properly or you know you need to get rid
of a a cookie somehow um playing around
with this cookie parsing logic of where
does this cookie end where does it start
with the double quotes with the single
quotes with backslashes with um
different uses of semi semicolons which
is the delimiter for cookie attributes
and that sort of thing all of those are
are really um uh High rate of success
techniques I think uh more than I I
thought so before reading this right up
yeah yeah so a couple um a couple
thoughts that I have on this um one it's
probably a good opportunity for some
sort of um automation or tooling around
testing cookie values for a couple
different you know escapes and
conditions and just alerting and saying
hey there's uh you know this cookie on
this endpoint
supports being encapsulated with boats
or something um that that's one thing
another thing um that I was thinking
about
is I would almost never test this and
it's such an interesting Gadget to have
found because I'm really guilty of
taking all the cookies in my request and
the first thing I do is I delete every
single one of them except for the ones
that I need because cookies like a lot
of time the cookie string is just really
long and like you know busy and it it I
I want to just be able to look around it
and so I'll say okay where's which one
of these is the off cookie I'll remove
everything else except for that one and
then I'll Minify my requests down to
just that and I don't even look at the
cookie values and so I I probably would
have never found this yeah yeah I I can
I can understand you know it's good to
know sort of like what's required in the
requests and to be able to identify you
know maybe unauthenticated requests or
or what part of the request is providing
authentication um but yeah I'm super
guilty of that so uh I I think testing
for the this and um testing those types
of values like inherently I don't even
know if like let's let's say you know
like the the reflection uh in the CSP
issue that by itself is not like really
an issue like yeah you can leverage it
like as it was demonstrated in the blog
but by itself is like you know what are
you going to do with that you have to
have something else that can set that
cookie and then you know actually like
Leverage it to trigger the xss um so
it's just one of those things that is a
super useful Gadget but testing it by
itself
um is is a very interesting thing like I
don't unless I was looking for something
explicit right like it was like okay let
me try and find a gadget that I can use
later or I I would probably do it in
reverse honestly if I found something uh
some excesss and I wanted to escalate it
being able to you know then find a
cookie that I can reflect yeah you know
well I I I agree I kind of think I think
in this scenario like a lot of times
cookie based xss is is sort of like an
open redirect like you don't really look
for it until you need it you know and
and and I think um and I think maybe
that's a little underrated because I I
think uh there's probably more stuff
there than we often go after because
we're not often really fuzzing stuff in
the in the cookies uh as like a matter
of habit or at least I'm not maybe some
I mean clearly some are um and I that
was one of the big takeaways I had as
well when when we were hacking together
um was like I I started sending you
stuff and you were like hm I wonder if
you know how this works and then you
were like oh here here I got it and you
had fuzzed the parameter names um with
like a static value and you'd found like
a hidden parameter um that allowed us to
do something and you know I was like oh
I I need to start doing that well the
the interesting thing about that was you
found this like crazy endpoint that's
like clearly like what was it like slash
render HTML or something like thatf
proxy exactly it's like okay we got to
figure out how this works um so so yeah
definitely in that scenario that was
that was the route I took but I I also
wanted to say um I saw I want to say it
was in the critical thinking Discord
Fran's comment on um the this write up
somebody had posted I want to say in the
cool research Channel and um and that he
had known about it like he he he he had
said like ah yeah that weird thing with
the you know on Zoom with the you
reflecting the script value into the you
into the HTML attribute so um I think
that's really interesting because it
shows that he at least was looking at
that sort of thing um which so I mean
that's another good positive indicator
if frog is doing something then maybe
you should be doing it too and it also
goes to show like the gadget thing is
very Universal where like yeah other
hackers probably know about that thing
and I've probably seen that behavior
especially if you're really familiar
with the program I think that's one big
thing I see a lot when people um I see
this all time at live hacking events
when hackers come together after hacking
on the same Target for two weeks there's
like a lingo almost where we're we're
just like oh yeah that behavior and like
everybody just sort of knows what you're
talking about because oh yeah the script
that thing yeah did you find a way to
use that like yeah so it's really
interesting um to see how everybody sort
of picks up some of the same identifiers
but nobody like it's usually only one or
two people who figure out the right way
to be able to leverage it or they piece
together like the the the correct chain
to actually exploit it that's that's the
crazy thing too Joel is like about going
to these live hacking events is the
amount of times that the thing that you
thought was interesting actually gets
exploited is like it's like 95% I can't
tell you how many times I've seen a show
in tell where they're like yeah so a lot
of people probably saw this thing and
and everybody just like
groans yeah dude it's so it's so crazy
but it it should be really inspiring
because it's like okay this thing that
you're looking at this thing that you're
playing around with you just haven't
given it enough time probably and and
you know a part of all this is knowing
when to quit you got to know when to
quit right like that's that's an
essential part um but and you know to
know your own limitations as a hacker
but as long as you can continue to idate
and you can continue to think about what
the possibilities are for some of these
uh you know gadgets that are floating
around I think there's there's value
there's a lot of value in that yeah yeah
like if you think about it right like
there only there's only so much depth
you can get out of certain things like
if if you find this CSP um injection you
you can mess with it to your heart's
content but I would almost guarantee
that you're never going to turn that by
itself into a bug and you could spend a
week straight poking different values
into there and it's going to give you
the same output you have to have some
you have to find something else that
allows you to actually leverage that to
use it so like knowing about it is one
thing but like just like with any bug
not everything that you find can be
directly turned into a bug sometimes you
have to leverage other things along with
it to actually make it into something I
remember I remember a scenar
where I was hacking with my menty uh mol
uh he's come on the Pod before I think
he was in the bug Bounty mentorship
episode and we we were hacking together
and he found this like absolutely sick
client side patch veral flow that used
like a post message and the implicit o
between a relationship between like a
window generated via client side path I
mean it was just it was an awesome bug
um but he couldn't exploit it because he
didn't have a an open redirect and I was
like okay you know I'll I'll poke around
see if I can find an open redirect and
so I started poking around and and like
15 minutes later I was like I got an
open redirect and he's like he's like
you what you freaking what you got an
open redirect and then he just like
jumps up and we like start screaming and
like you know and he puts it into the
chain I know Target you're talking about
too because I had asked you like I had I
had a we had a very very almost bug uh
on the same Target and I was like hey
you have an open redirector you're like
uh no actually it's the right kind of a
read like HTP or need to be htps or
something like that yeah yes you clearly
know the target um so so yeah but in
this scenario it ended up working and
and and it was like sometimes you just
got to go got to go hunt for those those
gadgets along the way um and I think as
you get your that's another skill in and
of itself is this sort of can I fill the
requirement of this this vulnerability
by finding a very specific Niche
function
you know um and I think that takes reps
just like everything else does in
hacking you got you got to get your reps
trying to find this gadget you know and
and get the hints
on looking at for an open redirect I
should look at the login functionality I
should look at the account linking
functionality like you know all these
areas where redirects commonly occur
yeah for sure I think it's it's
definitely a different skill set to be
able to think sort of cross
functionality within the application
like that and probably the hardest part
of being like a
really getting to that next level of top
hacker is being able to go from just
like single sort of level
vulnerabilities where it's like here's
an idore here's you know what and then
combining functionalities to piece
together a vulnerability and having
these multiple different things across
the application that you can click
together and say oh yeah there's there's
this thing that I can leverage to you
know set the cookie here which will then
force it to redirect to here which will
then take me to Google which you know
and being able to to piece those things
together in in a successful way instead
of just having them as separate ideas or
just not even you know having those
notes I think that's that the real hard
part it's a it's a force of will thing
too it's like all right I'm gonna I'm
going to bend this application to my
will you know I'm G to make it happen
and I think that's a really valuable
part so we talked about this right up
tangentially for like 15 minutes now I
do want to add one more thing before we
move long um which is I think there is
another like one cookie tossing if you
don't know what it is you need to figure
it out uh because it's super helpful it
tldr is you can use a subdomain to set
cookies for the top level domain and
that cookie gets sent to all the
different domains and you can specify a
more specific path so that your your
cookie gets prioritized when it's sent
in extremely extremely valuable um tool
in the hacker tool kit so research that
if you're not a master of it already um
the other the other tip was I really
like and I've seen this before but I I
kind of I don't know it it hadn't it
hadn't really like fully seeped into my
brain yet I think I could have figured
out it out in the scenario if I needed
it but I just figured I'd shout it out
here again is like this whole concept of
switching the response type in in an
ooth flow to code uncore ID token I mean
um uh sorry code comma idore token right
and and what that does is it because the
token can't be sent in in the queer
parameters like the code can it will put
the code and the ID token in the hash
and the beauty of that is that you don't
have to even like have an endpoint that
requires you to or you know uh allows
you to like hand it a token or anything
like that you can just take the hash
back out and put it in the query
parameter when you're finishing your
exploit if you're able to leak that hash
um and I just think that's that's pretty
nice because it's like you don't have to
find any sort of alternative flow
alternative gadgets or anything you just
smuggle the piece of information you
need in a different medium because uh of
the caveat of also sending the ID token
along with it I thought that was really
Co yeah yeah for sure it's it's
interesting that it behaves that way
it's very similar format to the um like
the scope uh parameter that you would
also send which you know comma delim
delim
delated uh delim whatever delated comma
separated there's a comma delimiter yeah
yeah yeah comma separ ated values of you
know ID profile email Etc um same type
of format here it there's a a couple
things that we talked about today that I
would be really interested to see sort
of like
a broad analysis of how these features
work across different implementations so
different um ooth libraries that are
being used to implement open ID um as
well as like the cookie thing for
example like different web Frameworks uh
that areow different framewor and just
see like how does Express handle this
how does pH handle this how does um you
know go handle this like all sorts of
things I'd be really interested if
somebody from the community wants to dig
me up on that free give us free research
yeah if you I tell you what if you make
a blog post about it we'll probably
shout it out so yeah well absolutely
will for sure um yeah absolutely and I
think I think uh the cookie the cookie
thing has got me thinking man so I don't
know I might take the dive and and do
some of that research myself because
there's we'll cover it we'll cover it
later we'll cover it later
okay next one on the list uh amazing
write up that I'm not even going to
attempt to uh consolidate into the audio
medium this is the SharePoint xxe write
up by chudy p pb uh it was posted by the
zero day initiative um and essentially
this is an easy on SharePoint and you
really need to go read the whole write
up because he does an awesome job of
explaining the whole flow of the exploit
and how he identified it what all the
turning points were what you know nested
code he was reading and how deep he went
um but I did want to shout out one thing
here which which was a takeaway for me
which is uh he was looking at a piece of
the SharePoint functionality where a you
know XML was pared so of course every
hacker ah xxe xxe but there's there's
very clearly um XML reader settings. DTD
processing is set to prohibit and and it
uses like safe XML safe resolver or
something like that right and it's like
okay this probably is invulnerable to
xxe but he still tries a couple things
against it and I'll just I'll just read
one little snippet from the from the
blog post now I decided to to play
around and send a general entity based
payload as some of the text code I wrote
similar to the code uh shown above um so
he sends in this General uh xxt payload
as Ed no HTP request was performed and a
DTD processing exception was thrown but
what about this payload and he provides
another another payload and I'm going to
try to attempt to describe this now so
typically with um you know doc types and
entities you've got your sort of Doc
type section you define an entity and
then that entity is then used in the XML
body right so you know within that it
value is evaluated and put into yes into
the X body right exactly um within an
element yeah so you'll see like a XML
tag and then you'll see Ampersand uh the
name of the entity and then a semicolon
and that that will be that entity will
be expanded when the uh XML document is
processed however what and that was the
one that that didn't work right however
what he does in this scenario is he
actually does the dock type definition
defines the entity and then references
The Entity inside of the dock type on
the next line so you've got the The
Entity line defining this uh SP variable
is the one that he chose in the specific
scenario and then directly below that
before closing the dock type he he just
writes uh percent sign SP semicolon to
reference that entity um and wow this is
an interesting one uh because it it
bypasses all of these uh uh
DTD processing settings and and I think
the reason for that is it it it
processes the the entities that are
there and then uh checks afterward after
it processes that whether the XML body
contains any of the like entities that
need to be expanded and if it is it says
no um and I just thought wow there's
probably a lot of sort of sketchy uh
blocking of XML entities out there uh
considering list of broadscale research
exactly like you know this is this is um
you know a pretty core net I want to say
this was net um functionality
here they were talking about how these
XML reader libraries are used pretty
pretty globally across that that
languages ecosystem and uh and this
still had this massive hole in it so
when when you're testing for xxe it
might be helpful to have several
variants of of processing in place that
have outbound calls as well uh because
there could be a sort of a niche uh
exception to that to that here so yeah
anyway so sorry for that super
longwinded explanation Joel no I
honestly like uh if it doesn't click
just open the write up on on zdi and
there's two little XML Snippets and
it'll say I decided to play around with
this one and it didn't work and then I
tried this payload and just look at the
two of them and it's a very very subtle
thing but if you know anything about XX
it's one of those things that like you
might try the first payload and just be
like all right XX is not possible here
they're blocking it and never try the
other one um and it kind of just goes to
show that you you know testing in depth
this is one of those moments where make
sure that you you know you've tested
sort of a bunch of different payloads
and a different bunch of different
options before you decide to move on not
just one yeah yeah I totally agree and
actually when you said you know look at
the two uh XML blobs I was like all
right Joel I'll look at the two XML
blobs and I and I actually iiz something
that I sort of missed before which was
the second blob there that contains the
payload that actually worked there's a
percent sign right after the entity um
uh tag before the name of the variable
and I think that so I just quickly
Googled it I think that is called a
parameter entity which uh the percentin
tells the XML processor to look up The
Entity name in the dtd's list of
parameter entities insert the value of
the entity into the DTD in the place of
The Entity reference and process the
value of the entity as part of the DTD
so it's like so I don't think you could
do and be in the doc type like that I
think you have to do it with percent
because it's a parameter it's basically
referencing the entry above exactly yeah
so it's like a way for you to
dynamically create
other uh you know dock type definitions
in in there I think so very very cool
idea um this is starting to ring some
Bells now I have seen something similar
to this before so I understand why why
he tried that but it is definitely
concreted in my brain now as like a core
core xxe must check sort of thing these
sort of uh uh parameter entities yeah
absolutely absolutely um okay last one
on the list before we get to today's uh
today's prepared uh educational
topic you like that new that new
uh section there I don't know thatly um
is
Shazer okay this is I you put this in
the dock and I was like what the heck is
this thing I look it up it's I I was
like trying to find out more about it
because I I I won't lie it's a cool tool
but there's like zero documentation
about what this thing is or how it works
or anything like that and the first
thing that caught my eye was there's a
lot of at the bottom of the page it says
like popular users and new users and
I've seen all these names of people that
I knew and I was like oh okay I these
people know what's up so let me let me
go check this thing out out and from
what I gather uh it's basically like um
a continuous sort of like testing
fuzzing platform for little Snippets of
like here's this function I want to call
or here's this this you know area that I
can inject into what are the possible
inputs that I can escape or what
characters can pass through this and
stuff like that and this was created by
none other than Mr Gareth Hayes over at
uh at portswigger research
Creator um and uh when I when I started
searching this thing I found a blog post
like announcing this thing from
2012 that was like here's this tool I
created called you know Shazer whatever
shared fuzzer and then yeah at the
bottom it says fuzzing browser is 2012
so this is like super old tool 12 years
old um been around for ages way ahead of
the curve and yeah it's really really
interesting there's a bunch of cool
things on here I think one of the cool
uh coolest things is this little cheat
sheet um page that's underneath the
vectors drop down at the top and it
basically just says uh you know it has a
bunch of different examples of
essentially cheat sheets that have been
generated by this tool that'll say you
know for example um you've got a
character um injection between the
exclamation point and the greater than
in an HTML comment what can I put in
there wow and then it'll tell you okay
the only thing you can put in there is a
greater than symbol um or you know
you've got uh a a multi-line string and
there's a backslash and you can input a
character in there what what what can
you put in right um and CR I don't know
if that's individually C and R or if
that's specifically a character turn um
yeah but it you know it has this for a
lot of things like ignored characters
and Json proper values this was
something that uh I didn't I didn't know
which was super interesting um you know
you can you can put like spaces at the
front of a value you can put a plus at
the front of the value and it'll just
ignore dude that was crazy to me like
yeah like if you do like X colon as a
string plus
1337 and you parse it as the Json object
it it'll just say x is 1 through 37 well
and it it will but the the caveat to
that is which they don't they didn't put
in the title of this one that I noticed
when I was like wait a second there's no
freaking way that works is uh is that
it's a loose comparison to an integer so
because it's a double equals yeah
exactly so it's not a strict converting
exactly it's it's implicitly converting
the string into a an integer but the the
interesting piece about that is like wow
okay I can put plus 1337 in a string and
then have that Loosely compared to an
you know an integer and it will actually
just drop the plus straight off the
front which I thought was really yeah
yeah that is super interesting so
essentially what this thing allows you
to do is take Define some templates
Define some js code that you um want to
use to fuzz something in the browser uh
and it will go ahead and run it against
uh the latest versions of chrome uh
Firefox and Safari and you can also note
the differences and I think that's a
really really cool piece of this is like
there's so many if you go to the the
Shazer doco.com
[Music]
browser market share stuff that um
Safari actually is very is very quirky
for one and has a very uh sizable amount
of the market share yeah yeah especially
because mobile browser right and and
webkit is across everything right so
it's not necessarily that a web kit bug
but if it affects Safari it's probably
going to affect Safari on iOS Mac OS
watch OS iPad OS right yeah man popping
a popping a smartwatch over there that'd
be that be something
I'm not going to lie that has been I I
I've seen many of the watch us
vulnerabilities end up coming through
stuff like web kit oh yeah and those
shared Frameworks that are on everything
what was that like I want to say there
was like some crazy iMessage bug that
came out earlier this year and it was
like you know it showed like a timeline
of the bug and it was like 12 different
bugs Chained and then just at the end
like you know it would get like you know
um code execution in like a a controlled
environment and then it would just pop
open the
browser and then just like pone the
system via some sort of uh browser
exploit which I thought I'm trying to
remember what you're talking I know the
one you're talking about oh man what was
that yeah look it up after yeah um
anyway super cool site go check out
chazzer very good stuff there yeah
Shazer co.uk another Gareth Hayes
awesome
tool hey guys real quick I just wanted
to give a shout to the content team they
have been absolutely killing it the past
couple months taking the content from
the podcast and condensing it down into
consumable social media posts whether it
be shorts or text posts or whatever
they've been rocking it so uh I just
wanted to give them a shout out and let
you know that they do all sorts of
cybercity content as well as social
media management they do technical blogs
they do uh comprehensive social media
management uh so if your organization
could benefit from any of those types of
services make sure you head over to
hacker content.com drop them a line and
mention the podcast when you do to get
your first month of cyber security
content marketing services for free all
right that's it let's get back to the
Pod um all right
so let me clear the throat really quick
let me uh let me get some coffee another
certified ctbb moment of 43 minutes of
news 43 minutes of
News man your boys can Yap can we not we
can y we are yappers yeah we we we are
engaging in yapping activities okay so
um let's let's go ahead and continue
that and what I kind of wanted to talk
to about today was match inter replace
Okay match and replace is I think
severely underrated uh by by top hackers
in particular because I think that there
is a lot of like okay you know if you're
just getting into bug Bounty you use to
match and replace you do this and that
and the other thing but I think a lot of
people stop using it and I think that's
a mistake because there's there is a lot
of there are a lot deeper layers you can
go into with match and replace um that
allows you to very quickly and easily
test an application when once you
already have a deeper understanding of
the application and some of and some of
these things really do require a more
thorough understanding of the browser
than a lot of people mention when
they're like oh beginner go try the you
know match and replace thing or whatever
so I kind of wanted to talk about some
of the the areas where I've seen some
success with this uh and I also wanted
to try to get your thoughts on if you
ever use this in a mobile hacking
environment because um there's I feel
like there'd be some weird stuff with
that since there isn't as an actual
client side uh of sorts I guess the
client side is like Java code um but let
let me start out with this so one of the
cool areas that I've seen with this is
actually using match and replace to turn
on and off feature flags and EXP
experiments and AB testing stuff and and
you you very often see this it could it
could be an HTTP request that gets
issued from the the JavaScript uh and it
oftentimes it's not even to this is the
tricky part okay oftentimes it's not
even in your your defined scope right
like it'll be reaching out to like
launch darkley or like um some of these
other feature flag controlling domains
um and it'll be like hey what feature
should I turn on for user XYZ
and then it'll be like here's a list you
know super admin functionality enabled
false you know and and just using a
match and replace rule to turn on all of
those will give you access to so much
more functionality and save you so much
time because at the end of the day we're
going to find the features because we're
just going to parse through the JS and
we're going to understand you know where
each of these endpoints are and we're
going to try to recreate the request but
man how much easier would it be if you
just clicked the button in in the
browser and it was like oh okay okay you
are a super admin and and you just get
to use the interface like it's intended
yeah that's one of my honestly one of my
favorite things to do is just set a
match into place to replace false to
true yeah and like nothing even specific
just false to True dude that just reeks
freaking havoc on the application though
it does it does but that's my favorite
thing is you know it it shows you so
many things that generally you wouldn't
see um you know sometimes it it it may
end up doing the opposite thing like you
know maybe they have is banned false and
then you set that one to True by
accident um but you know it helps you
sort of narrow down where you want to
you know you you can narrow it down
later and be more specific on you know
which endpoints it replaces on or
whatever um but just setting false the
true is is a great thing I would
encourage this is a little I'll I'll
just drop this go to hacker one and uh
set your proxy to replace false the true
don't don't okay so you're gonna see a
lot of really interesting things oh my
gosh Joel yeah and and and I think I
think that is
a that is one of my first um exposures I
think to match and replace was I
remember very pointedly talking to none
other than Mr Mark Lichfield himself the
the king of uh you know Finding weird
little little techniques and and if you
if you talk to him he's very humble you
know he he'll say like he's very humble
in some ways uh but when I was talking
to he was very very humble about like
okay you know I don't actually know that
much about how all this stuff works but
I found that if uh what he's really good
at is understanding the the logic of the
application the business Logic the
application and that sort of thing and
he's like if I set false to to True with
a match and replace role then I see a
bunch of extra stuff and then I can kind
of go through here and dig through all
these requests and document it and that
sort of thing I was like okay that's
weird why does that work that way and
then I started looking you know deeper
into it and and you see some of this
stuff um and I think setting false to
True is sort of the naive approach to
this whole thing and you will get some
results out of this but you will get
much better results if you actually just
look at the HTML Page look at the API
request that's turning on feature Flags
or or look at if you determine the way
that the the front-end application is
being informed about what role you are
or what features you have enabled and
then you design a custom match and
replace rule to enhance that either you
look at the JavaScript and you extract
all the roles and you match and replace
that into the roles um array that's
coming back from uh uh the API request
or you you um you look at at the request
that's saying is this feature enabled is
this feature not enabled then you know
you match and replace those to to True
um you'll get a lot of good results on
that and I think just to your to what
you were saying there Joel about just
changing false to true I think this
works a lot better when you use kaido's
conditional match and replace which I
haven't I maybe I'm just not as familiar
with how to do this in burp but but I
haven't seen a way to do this in burp
where you essentially say okay if the
request path uh is something like this
then replace false with true so then it
becomes much more like much less uh
destructive you're not taking your
Javascript file and then just saying
every time false is in a Javascript file
turn it to true instead you're saying
you can define a specific path and then
switch false to true yeah so in burp as
far as I know the only way to do it is
basically like an All or Nothing type of
way where on kaido each individual match
replace rule can have its own conditions
burp is either you know apply this to in
scope and then you can Define in scope
how you want it uh or it just doesn't
apply at all to any to anything like
that um or you can I think you say like
it you know it has to be the URL has to
match a certain like you can do it but
again those rules are like all or
nothing it's not yeah yeah yeah it's not
like per rule yeah and so I think that's
a really cool Fe feature of kaido and I
think also I've been talking with the
team because uh I I really want them to
put extra effort into the match and
replace feature and um I actually wrote
a uh sort of some augmentations some um
some things that make the match into
place stuff better and I I put that into
even better the kaido extension um where
you can just sort of Select some text
right click Send a match and replace and
it will autop populate the the name and
the the matching string in match inter
replace for you and then you can just
easily create your rule um so definitely
some cool stuff there I I they have also
the Kido team has also mentioned that
they will potentially at some point
allow for a Rex plus convert workflow um
match and replace which would be really
awesome and I think how that would work
is you define a redx that matches it and
then that match is then passed into a
convert workflow which is a kaido
construct where you can um perform sort
of hack verter esque um modifications to
that data so you can URL in code you can
B 64 in code you can do whatever and
this is the best part you can just run
JavaScript um so then you know you have
access to a bunch of different things
you can shell out you can do all sorts
of stuff um and I'm excited for that
because I think that will add a little
bit more um that that will allow for you
to match things that are not static and
turn turn them all into something that
is Rel relative to what it was so if you
have some integer that needs to increase
uh with every match or something like
that then you can do that with the
convert workflow and I have run into a
couple scenarios where I just have to
manually create a [__] ton of match
inter replace rolls to get it to do what
I want it to do so I'm excited for that
feature to roll that as well yeah yeah
super awesome and I think like that's
one of the really awesome things about
kaido is that it has it has like
built-in flexibility right where burp I
think you basically to do any of this
you'd have to install some sort of
extension that allows you to do it where
this is sort of just native
functionality that's built in and then
there are extensions but usually those
extensions are using the built-in
functionality yeah um it's not you know
behind some SDK or something like that
um and even just recently I I wrote a
convert workflow that uh just made a
shell command basically like so I could
work you know originally it was from for
burp it was honestly doing the same
thing was just like calling a script and
I was like here let me just convert this
over to kaido um and just turn it into
workflow that calls the same script and
yeah it works great yeah yeah it it's
surprisingly um I think there's still a
they're still working on backend plugins
and stuff like that with kaido but there
is a lot of flexibility that comes along
with um passive workflows and active
workflows and convert workflows with
just those those three constructs you
can do a lot of stuff um a lot of
implementing your ideas into automation
very quickly without having to build a
whole plugin which I think is is pretty
rad
um all right so back to the match and
replace stuff um this is another sort of
um maybe something that isn't really
often uh categorized with match and
replace is this whole ability to save
yourself some time this is such real
[__] too dude like to save yourself some
time on going down a wrong aath path
because what I'll often see is like I'll
make assumptions about the application
I'll see okay I'm thinking of the
specific scenario so I'll just give you
the specific scenario there was a um an
input that I could provide to a front
end page that would then get passed into
uh a fetch request and then be reflected
in the body of the response and then
that that um piece of of data would then
be put directly into
window.location.href so I'm thinking
okay great I can if I can get it to hit
a JavaScript URL and it just goes
straight to window location. H then I
can get access
and it you know let me start fuzzing
around with this thing and there was
some really weird stuff and I was like
ah I'm pretty close I think I can get
this so I was like H I'm going to spend
some time fuzzing this trying to like
figure out what characters I can put in
there to get it to accept it and um and
then right as I was about to go down
that whole like 30 minute Rabbit Hole I
was like wait a second let me just
validate this attack strategy really
quick without having to go and parse
through like 25,000 lines of JavaScript
and um and figure out whether this is
going to work so I just took the value I
just put in like an accepted value I
matched and replaced it to a a
JavaScript URL and I I popped it in
there and lo and behold it was not going
to work there was there was uh there was
some other way that it was doing it that
wasn't compatible with that and uh and
it was doing some checks along the way
that was were never going to be
compatible with the jav script URL um
and I could see that very quickly uh
because I just used match and replace to
quickly validate whether this attack
path that I was going down was actually
going to work in the end or not um so I
think this is sort of like a a um threat
model validation or like a um attack
Vector validation method as well that
can save you some time is just really
quickly doing a match in place rule
validating what you're thinking about
and then deciding whether to go down
that path or not yeah because I think
otherwise you'd probably have to set a
bunch of break points and Chase down
stuff in the driv and that would also
work but it would take a lot more time
and energy and effort to try and find
that exact thing and sometimes your
breakpoints don't trigger and you're
just like you're going to spend 30
minutes just banging your head against
the wall and the freaking Dev console
man you know I love it and I use it
every day but it's like there it's it's
much nicer to just very quickly just do
a little match and replace thing because
it's so quick and easy you could
validate your attack strategy in 20
seconds you know so it's definitely
that's definitely another sort of
underrated usage of it I think
um all right so I've got three more
let's see let's let go with uh okay
another under underrated uh
implementation I think of of match in
place is actually match and replacing
JavaScript files uh which is a little
bit counterintuitive because it's like
okay uh normally we're just kind of
modifying data in HTML or in API
requests but essentially what I was able
to do one time was I was kind of susing
out uh I I'll be public about this
target this was Google bard and uh and I
was kind of assessing out the way that
they had their feature Flags implemented
because Google bard was under like Mega
rapid development right like they were
cranking out features for that thing
every single day like it was very
important to Google to get features out
ASAP um and so I was like okay well
they've got to be there's got to be some
some feature flag stuff surrounding this
so I was kind of ssing it out and I
found this one function that was like is
this feature enabled and it would return
like true or false right and I was like
okay wait a second so I just match and
repl like wrote a match and replace rule
to just make that function always return
true so I didn't even have to do this
whole thing where it was like okay let
me let me um you know match and replace
enable enable true for like this
specific one and that specific one
because they were all sort of encrypted
in a weird way in true Google fashion um
and and so I just match and replace to
that one thing to true and all of a
sudden boom like my screen just lit up
with new features and I found like five
or six bugs from it um yeah I had a very
similar thing happened just the other
day actually where um I was I was
looking at again Feature Feature flag
type thing there's a there was a
function in the JavaScript that was
being called every single time it would
pass in like this key for the feature
name and then it would return whether or
not it was enabled and so I just looked
for CS of that and instead uh I replaced
it with um true you know
just you know I I actually I believe I
chained it together where I did like
variable equals call and then I just did
equals call equals true and then ah
there you go yeah yeah nice so so you
replaced any reference to that with a a
something that evaluated to true that's
a great idea it doesn't even call the
function it just it just replaces it
with true that's cool yeah so so I think
imine replacing JavaScript there's
there's a couple different applications
of it I think as well um this was just
the one that I had most freshed by brain
um one of the other things that I've
kind of seen with this is like there
will be a weird Edge case sometimes with
um webp packed JavaScript where the
browser is like oh I know I know what
this does and it'll like try to try to
expand it or whatever and then you're
trying to go through and you're trying
to like set break points and it won't do
it and it's like some statement call
that is outside of an if statement will
get triggered even though the statement
isn't true or something like that and
essentially what's happening is is the
browser is messing up the the
Reconstruction of that that minifi
JavaScript file um and it's showing you
something that's not accurate so so
there's a little button down at the
bottom of the of the um Dev console
that's like uh see the source where this
originally came from I forget what what
the button actually says but it's like
you can click on it it'll show you the
location in the minified source but then
if you try to do anything to that
minified Source it'll just be like you
want to see the unminified source don't
you and then it'll like send you back to
the the unminified source and you're
like so um so what what I do in that
scenario is I'll set up a match inter
replace rule to just remove the The
Source map um and just say like just
just don't do it browser please
interesting and uh and then you know you
refresh it and now you're just dealing
with the minified source which despite
being very difficult to read is always
the source of truth right because that's
the code that it's actually running um
and you can make your modification there
that's interesting I've never had to do
that although maybe I have and just
haven't done it yeah Joel is sitting
there like why is this break point I'm
thinking like you know there's definely
a lot of annoying cases that where I've
just like given up and like done
something else to get around that um
because I'll like said something that I
know should be happening it's just not
yeah Dev tools Dev tools can be a [__]
sometime man it really can so yeah it is
what it is um all right uh of course
this would not be a comprehensive match
and replace uh episode if I didn't talk
about paywall bypasses in rback testing
I did sort of mention a little bit um
the fact that you should really try to
dive into the JavaScript a little bit
try to look at the API calls and figure
out exactly where they're making
decisions about what kind of user you
are um and I'll I'll share a personal
little anecdote about this the other day
I've got a
mentee um and he
was I I told him hey I found some bugs
here with matching rep place I think
there's probably some more here's the
place I'm busy for the next you know
week or whatever try to see if you can
find some bugs and uh and you know we'll
split them because I gave you the hot
lead on it and I showed you exactly how
to do it and he's like okay great so he
gets in there and um he starts poking
around and he starts setting up these
match and replace roles and I just sort
of saw the role uh end point in the in
the uh uh like in this sort of
environment and was like okay great this
is where it's happening and I like you
know matching placed all the roles in
there and I saw my screen light up and a
bunch of features turned on and I was
like great and I found some bugs and I
got excited and I was like this is the
way right and but I said okay I'm not
going to tell you exactly how to do it
so you can try to figure out how to do
it yourself go check it out and so he
found that but he also found something
that I didn't find which was like this
little um boan that's at like the very
end of a massive blob of of data inside
a script tag in the HTML page that was
like is admin you know is moderator true
false and I'm like oh man if of course I
had seen that you know that'd be great
and it was it wasn't like his admin it
was actually his moderator so it didn't
really I didn't you know when I searched
for admin it was didn't like pop up or
anything but um turning that on gave him
access to a whole another set of of
functionality in the web app just from
that one Boolean rather than having to
do the whole complex like roll thing um
so he got access to a bunch of stuff
that I didn't get access to and then I
was kind of poking in there around there
with him and we found like CLI side PSAL
piece that was in there um that would
only affect the moderators uh and so
there's there's definitely some some
value in really being thorough about
your assessment and even if you found
where you think the the application is
doing those rback decisions or those
roll decisions taking it another layer
deeper really being thorough with that
and trying to undercover or uncover
every single little decision or um
decision on what should be displayed in
the application yeah yeah for sure I
again this is one of the instances where
it just keep it simple you know keep
keep it simple is uh when you know how
to how to use so many tools it's easy to
want to use those tools to fill very
specific use cases but a lot of times
it's just more complicated than it needs
to be um and you know you you'll write
some really complicated reject or
something or you'll go and you'll set
all these break points and really you
should just be doing a match and replace
for just a single string and just keep
it simple so you can keep your testing
moving um instead of getting sidetracked
and pulled away into this this sort of
rabbit hole of like doing it correctly
or doing it very precisely and
accurately yeah and and re-evaluating
and making sure that you are you know
hitting all these different spots like
because you could make the same mistake
that I did going down this route of like
ah the rolls that's the whole our back
you know and there's actually another
section that you missed um so that
that's a good shout there um the other
one that I was going to mention here is
paywall bypasses which you know I don't
know maybe am I the only one that calls
them paywall bypasses because I feel
like I I searched this up the other day
and there isn't a bunch of stuff on
like reading materials yeah there's not
like a bunch of articles on this V type
so
maybe I it's under some some other name
but the I call playw Bypass is
essentially when there is some
functionality that's behind a pay wall
you need to be a premium subscriber to
access XYZ feature
um and you're able to bypass that um and
these are very impactful bugs because I
know that I personally paid a decent
chunk of money let's just say that for
access to a software that I use every
day that makes my life super much better
and I love it uh but I only needed one
feature that the premium for that for
that software was going to add and then
I found out afterwards that that
software has a bug Bounty program and I
was like wait a second and I started
poking at it and I was actually able to
access that feature without going
through the without paying for it it was
a pay wall bypass on that and I reported
it and it got paid and it was great and
it paid for my subscription to that
software for a long time um but I
wouldn't have you know if I were a
malicious user I wouldn't have paid for
that software uh because I I had just
accessed this feature and it was a very
simple very simple exploit to that a
non-technical user could could have
found um one thing I will say is paywall
bypasses often it's very Case by case so
some programs it's just an accepted risk
or it's it's you know it's not something
that's easy to exploit at scale and so
they don't they won't really either
they'll lower the severity significantly
or it's just like um not like a huge
like security risk for them but a lot of
times you can use those pay wall
bypasses to test other features where
you will find bugs and then again you
can sort of like chain that together or
you can leverage that to to get a more
impactful exploit um and access that
attack surface without having to pay for
it yeah we we often talk about just
paying the price well wouldn't it be
cool if you just didn't pay it and you
still got access to the feature so uh I
just think about like paywall bypasses
kind of like you know wa W bypasses
right it's it's it's more of a barrier
to other things than it is like
necessarily a bug by itself it can be a
bug by itself but um you know I I see it
more as like a barrier to other features
and other functionality that you can
test it's interesting you say that
because I actually I have had a lot of
success with paywall bypasses man like
like I I I think I've been like I don't
know talking about this specific bug
type before and and people are like ah
yeah payall bypasses like yeah sometimes
they pay for those and I'm like what
like I mean it's not really a security
bug right it's like it absolutely is I
mean there is like a an access control
being bypassed but other than that it's
like it doesn't affect user data or
anything like that it's more of a
business it's more like a business
impact than it is ah business logic yeah
or something like that yeah like it it
affects like the the revenue side of the
business more than it does like any like
like it's not
like you know what I mean it's not like
a standard security
vulnerability sort of I think the
revenue for a business is pretty
important it depends right and so
especially with high dollar high dollar
products you know if it's like you know
something that's like five bucks a month
or whatever then it's you know they may
not care but to be honest man I found
paywall bypasses on on like very very
nominal fee stuff on massive companies
and they still paid it and I'm like huh
let me just look at this bounty like
this bounty is like you know this this
bug would have had to have been
exploited like 50 times for for this
bounty to actually cover the loss that
they made so you know there there is
some sort of um there some sort of
nuance to it but I also think that there
is a desire from these companies to be
very thorough with their with their
security assessments especially
companies that are are running pug
Bounty programs um and so I my
experience has been that if you can show
impact if you can show like a like a
pricing Matrix table that says hey you
should not be able to configure the you
know single sign on for a non Enterprise
organization and you can and it works
for like a pro level organization or
something like that and there's a little
X in the Box for pro and there's a
little you know check mark in the Box
for for business then they're normally
TR of having documentation for your
product
is reading it like that's the you know
and and and if you never make
documentation then they can't call you
out on it exactly man I love I love when
I find documentation that's like you
know this is goes to back to the whole
Douglas day thing where it's like look
for the nose in the application I love
it when we come across in documentation
it's like XYZ user should absolutely not
be able to do you know whatever and I'm
like let me just screenshot this bad boy
right here and just drop him right into
the report and uh I don't know I feel
like that kind of makes it bulletproof
personally um so well there there's two
takes for you guys on on the paywall
bypassing thing it seems like Joel has
also not had as much luck with it I
would say my paywell bypasses get
accepted 95% of the time
so yeah yeah I think it yeah it
definitely depends on the business
that's that's what I've observed
interesting um all right last one uh
before oh also I do want to hear from
you about well let's just go there now
is there is there any applications for
match and replace inside of a mobile
environment I mean obviously you've got
similar sort of things where like I I
think a lot of yeah I think like a lot
of the things that we talked about um
already apply here as well especially
with like Json replies you know like
hitting an endpoint to check if you're
this role or if you have these
permissions or fetching what feature
flags are turned on or off that's very
very common for mobile because like you
said it's not um it's not like a client
side application in the sense that it's
using HTML and the web and JavaScript to
do all that it's making individual API
calls taking those responses parsing
them using those results to do things
within the client app like to enable a
debug menu or to enable some feature or
you whatever so it's almost a little
more straightforward in the fact that
you're generally going to be getting
straight Json or API responses that you
can modify and and match replace on
those responses or requests then you
would have to go and dig through a a
Javascript file and find the call that's
enabling a feature flag you can also do
it you know less of a match replace but
like with Fredo right where you go and
you find maybe there's you know
oftentimes there's a feature flag
function within the Java you go find
that call you just return true um for
every you know input or whatever and
it's a similar type of thing but a
little more involved than just on the
API level yeah yeah no that that makes a
lot of sense yeah that you just have to
implement that I guess at the at the
Java level if you want to address it
from a JavaScript perspective or if you
wanted to actually use match and replace
in an HTTP proxy then you would you
would do it at the API API level um yeah
that that makes sense I had I had
something else that I wanted to ask you
about that and it's escaping my my mind
right now oh oh that's what it was so so
like in these mobile applications
sometimes there there is this whole
piece of like client side features that
I feel like is a little bit more
expected than in like a browser because
the phone has actual functionality like
like for example like oh we can't like
take a picture and like apply a certain
filter to it or something like that when
you don't have the premium product or
whatever right but all of that stuff is
client side so all of that is is in the
the Java code you know if we're talking
about an Android app for this
application so and and I did run across
this really interesting thing the other
day where I was like oh I'd kind of like
to be able to
um like proxy web web traffic a little
bit and and if it's doesn't have C
pinning then what what you can do from
what I've seen is even with a non
jailbroken phone you
can stand up a um VPN on the actual
device itself on a high high level port
or a high port number right then
configure your your device to go through
the VPN on the device and proxy some
traffic through there and this is a
non-rooted thing so I I think it would
be really interesting if they don't have
C pinning to to provide that as some
sort of demo which is like we have this
app it automatically does proxying um
there's no Sur pinning so it just
essentially match and replaces uh the
role to true and now we have access to
all these client side features just from
installing this like upgrade your you
know whatever filter app for free you
know APK file um and now you get access
to these features so what do you think
about that sort of pay wall bypass in a
mobile context yeah I mean it's
definitely trickier because there's
going to be like system level there's a
lot of like system level protections and
stuff so
um you know a lack of Sur pining in the
app there still might be Sur pinning on
the system you know what I mean like
it's going to check if the certificate's
valid um yeah but if you install it as a
VPN it will trust the the certificate
that's associated with the
VPN yeah and then that again like that's
you know a whole another level of the
user has to install it as a VPN and
right so there there are definitely like
layers to it I think and this is what
makes it challenging to have like really
high impact mobile bugs is like usually
there's a lot of weird caveats or like
system level things that are kind of in
your way um but I think it's still you
know you could if you could put together
a PC for it and get it to work like
cleanly you know I think that's it's
certainly a valid PC like again I I
don't think it's out of the question
that you could an attacker would have
control over some app on your phone
whether it's through compromising a
developer account or compromising or you
know getting you to install an APK that
ends being malicious or something you
know it it does happen um one thing I
was talking I I just did an episode with
Greg um from BB reports to see that yeah
yeah and
um he we we were talking about you know
it might be nice to see some numbers
from probably Google on what they
observe as this like the frequency rate
of this stuff happening like how often
does somebody have a malicious third
party app on their phone how often does
a developer account get compromised how
often does a malicious app make it
through the Play Store I'm sure they
don't really want to talk about those
numbers because it doesn't look great
for them um but I would be really
interested to know from like a impact
standpoint trying to evaluate that how
you can sort of
quantify how often a it How likely it is
for a user to actually go through these
scenarios because that would make it a
lot easier for hackers and programs to
sort of get on the same page about um
the likelihood of these sort of events
happening and if it's a high likelihood
okay then you know programs should
probably be paying more for this or or
adjusting and saying okay this is
actually kind of likely but if it's not
something that happens all the time or
rarely ever happens at all then I think
it's fair to say you know there's a
strong mitigating Factor here there is
an issue you know to some extent that
you know they may or may not decide to
fix but um you know the overall impact
might be a lot lower because of just the
likelihood for exploit yeah dude that's
a great that's an awesome point I would
love to see some data on that from from
Google and while you were talking about
that I was just scrolling through my
phone looking at all the apps and I'm
I'm just like man you know like you
install these like shitty little apps
for like all these little edge cases
like oh I got to like Park in Idaho you
know now I got to like for install it
and and then like that that app just
sits there and then they lose the
government contract and like the company
goes under and they sell their little
app you know and it's how easy would it
be to just buy some of these apps that
have millions of installs
was saying to Greg Greg was like
especially with telegram stealer list
nowadays you have to imagine that at
least one aptive elbert's on there oh
yeah um who's had their their creds gun
stolen and now you can compromise an app
and all you have to do is figure out the
the methods that all these malware devs
are figuring out to sneak stuff through
you know the Google Play Store Integrity
uh scanners or whatever and um you know
compromise an app it doesn't even have
to be like malware right it just has to
do like a very specific malicious action
or something like say you're trying to
exploit some specific bug on an app that
might not look at like malware um and
you know all they have to do is
compromise the developer so I wouldn't
be surprised if that's already happening
to some extent but I would be curious
again to see what the actual numbers are
on that both from a program and a hacker
perspective just on like what is the
likelihood of this because I think right
now the common sort of um understanding
is that these things do happen but not
that often and it's hard to say how
often it happens happens and How likely
it is yeah absolutely man I know there
are some people from Google listening to
this podcast so if you're at Google
reach out to your people try to make
this happen um I know bini I think is on
the Android team at Google so we should
probably reach out to him because he
might have some introspection into that
sort of thing yeah um all right last
thing on the match and replace that is
header Replacements and I think this is
pretty niched and sometimes has some
some application but um the two ones
that I I came down or I wrote down with
was host header modification so
essentially like this is pretty common
in the world of people that do hacking
based off of um SSL certificates uh so
what will happen is like you'll you'll
scan the whole internet for SSL
certificate you know using something
like search. or or showan or whatever
and um and you'll get back this this
host that has an SSL certific for like
you know test123 atsite or. site.com
right and you try to resolve test1 123.
site.com and it doesn't resolve either
that DNS record is on an internal DNS
server that's not responding to um sort
of requests outside of the organization
uh or they just deleted the record and
left the server up and so you're like
okay you try to visit that IP and it's
like you know generic 404 Apache or
whatever right because it's got a a
vhost set up for for that specific
purpose um so obviously you could go
into your Etsy host file or whatever and
like static the IP to that or you could
just say okay let me do a match and
replace rule in kaido and say match host
colon IP address replace it with host
test1
123.sc and then now you're navigating
that site as if there was a DNS record
that was resolving to that domain and um
and you're making you're making requests
you're interfacing with the app like
that um yeah I wanted to check and see
if kaido had it I didn't see really when
I looked really quickly right now but
this is one thing I do actually like
about burp that there's a static routing
table that you can um add entries into
can yeah and you could just say this
host should resolve to this IP and so
you can basically it's like a um like a
host file just within burp within your
proxy and you can route stuff to Local
Host you can you know route hosts to
whatever IPS that you want um and that's
super helpful for doing this exact type
of thing where maybe you have an IP that
resolves to or you have a host that
resolves to an internal IP or to a dead
IP or that doesn't resolve and you need
it to resolve to an IP um and you can
configure those on a case-by Case basis
without having to go and edit your host
file or do a matching replace like that
wow that's super awesome this is this is
a great this is a great thing about burp
and you know you guys know I'm a kaido
fanboy but I will give credit where
credit is due burp has you know I don't
know how old are they they're pretty
they're pretty old like 15 freaking
years 20 freaking years of of features
that they've integrated into burp and
it's just a lot of really Niche stuff
that is super helpful for Mega Niche
situations so um I think it definitely
pays to still know how to use burp and
and uh 20 years old wow is it 20 years
old wow and uh June of 2 oh it's over 20
years old holy cow June of 2003 burp
sweep 1.0 launched wow yeah look at this
okay so if you go to proxy proxy
settings you go to the network tab under
the settings and you look for
connections there's this host name
resolution override Ste that you can
provide uh host name overrides which is
your own little Etsy Etsy hosts in the
uh yeah in the inside burp that's really
awesome that's a great feature uh and I
like I like that because it it applies
it just for that specific project too um
you you don't get your Etsy host file
all all clogged up and I'm always
concerned whenever I modify my Etsy host
file I'm like man I'm going to leave
this in here I'm never going to go back
just like the apps man you set it once
and forget it in 6 months from now
you're going to be like what the heck is
going on with my computer exactly or or
like I'm gonna go to you know that that
host is gonna like come alive again and
I'm gonna have it redirect into this old
IP or something like that and it's going
to be like you know no no response from
the server and and then freaking you
know somebody in the live hacking event
is going to be like well I went to test1
123. site and this whole website web app
popped up and then I popped 15 CRPS and
you go and you and you're like what the
heck I swear I looked at that you open
it on your local it doesn't work and
that's when you find out that it was
Etsy house man it's like uh uh that sort
of thing happens man it happens so um
yeah all right cool well that's that's a
wrap I think I don't I don't oh this was
um there was one other header Joel
what's the other header yeah exort it
for this is one that oh man um so often
there are web proxies that either
incorrectly filter this out or
completely allow it to go through and
especially if it's passing headers
through to internal requests and stuff
maybe it's doing like a secondary
contacts type thing where it's making a
a separate request and it's taking your
IP address a lot of times if there's a
web proxy and some complicated stack
it's going to merge all those entries
together I've seen this before we saw
this very recently actually um where it
was basically building an x44 header
internally and it was combining uh the
IP addresses into one but it was taking
the x44 from the request and it was
using it as the first IP in the chain um
and case case sensitive oh my goodness
this is like a this one will come bite
you all the time because we found this
one recently where X4 to4 capital x
capital F capital F blocked doesn't work
xed four with any of those three changed
to a
lowercase just one little character off
no totally totally fine Works IP allowed
um so yeah that's a really weird one and
a lot of the time you'll find that your
fuzzing tools like fuff um this was an
annoying One fuff auto Capital it like
does title case on headers so it if you
give it all lowercase x forwarded for it
will change the X to capital x forwarded
capital F for capital F and you'll get
you know IP blocked unless you test it
manually I was testing it manually
through kaido and I found oh yeah sweet
this works I go to try and fuzz it can't
get it to fuzz because buff keeps auto
title casing and I can't force it to do
like even with a r request it wouldn't
go through so that's just something to
keep in mind um you know if you're doing
a lot of like at scale scanning and
stuff and you're hitting some IP blocks
or anything test it out locally first
test different cases on that x fored 4
test different spacing on the X fored 4
try like empty commas or just dummy IPS
um you know there's a lot of different
things you can do sometimes you can
escape out of that value sometimes you
can inject a new header depends on how
it's being used so um yeah x44 is always
a a great way to try and get around some
of those IP restrictions yeah absolutely
and I think the scenario that we were
looking at before it gave us some nice
like super great verbose eror message it
was like you're not allowed to like IP
whatever is not allowed to access this
and we're like okay yeah okay very
interesting what if I wasn't me though
yeah and and then it was like sure um so
no that's great but also I think this is
a pretty easy thing to to fuzz for too
you know if you're doing if you're just
trying to find stuff that's weird at
scale you know um checking for xed for
with various values and then checking
for X fored for with various casing was
not something that I've I've tried
before so I think that's that's a great
call out Joel um yeah oh yeah and then
the actual application for this with
match and replace is like once you find
this sort of weird caveat is that you
can just add the the header in Via match
and replace uh just match a blank a
blank line on the header and it will
just throw the header in um and then you
can navigate that application as if you
you know that that header was always
there from the reverse proxy or whatever
um y so yeah yeah so mat replace it does
have a lot more use than just adding
your username or that required header
that's in the scope page uh you know
that's that's the first step I like that
that that's sort of the point for a lot
of people to find this feature but um I
would encourage everybody to sort of dig
deeper and and try and maximize um the
value that you can get that you can get
out of it because there's there's a lot
of stuff that you can do with it dude I
was actually so I was planning on ending
the episode here and I know you got to
run here in a second but I also realized
that um this is also a pretty decent a
pretty decent way that you can use match
and replace is for storing payloads as
well uh so let's say you've got this
like um
you've got this sort of xss payload or
whatever right and instead of typing it
out out every time you just kind of put
like xss payload or whatever into the
thing and have it match and replace to
something now I will I will caveat this
with the fact that uh it will it it is
not context to wear so if you if you you
know say xss payload and it and your
returns it into response no no no no no
no in the request in the request so you
have to send it to the request um uh you
have to set it to request body or
whatever but um if you put it you know
let's say you put xss payload into like
a a form and you and you press submit
and then you have a match in place role
to convert xss payload to your whatever
xss payload it is if it's sending a Json
request out and your ACC payad contains
a double quote then it's just GNA screw
the whole Json and break everything so
it's not like the best technique for
this you know you have to be aware of
how the app is actually using this but I
actually have seen it in scenario I
where like you're wanting to put a blind
xss payload in your user agent or like
um there's a specific set of like um
headers and stuff like that that you
want to inject this stuff into or or
maybe there's a specific Niche payload
that you would have to type a lot using
a different character set on your
keyboard wow very specific example there
um and you have to switch back and forth
and your fingers hate it um then you can
you can just write the match and play
Rule and just have it auto insert it so
uh that's another another use case that
I didn't have down in the notes that I
just sort of popped into my brain yeah
maybe maybe in the future with the more
um the more complex use cases for match
and replace um like if if kaido decides
to go a step further than just the
conditional matches but also like having
the workflows or something like that you
could do more advanced like checking
each parameter and then check the
content type and if it's Json and code
it this way you know that sort of thing
and and have it more bespoke yeah that
absolutely should be possible with the
convert workflows because that we I was
talking to the team as well about like
hey you know we definitely with convert
workflows and with um these other types
types of workflows too but specifically
with convert workflows we need some way
to access the core request that it came
through even if that isn't the input
that's being passed in so we can get
context surrounding our our um our you
know conversion that needs to happen is
this conversion happening in a you know
xww form encoded environment is it
happening in a put put request in a you
know what's going on is it a parameter
or is it a body body you know yeah
exactly so I think that will also be
something we'll see implemented in the
future which I think will be which I've
actually seen you do in a in you know
what I'm talking about yeah yeah yeah
there's there's a um that one's actually
public so yeah I have done that before
yeah yeah yeah the yeah you created a a
a convert workflow for no a from uh from
chubs during the nahaman talk exactly
and uh it basically checks you know what
content typee is this and it will
generate the payload based on that
content type whether it's should be a
comment or an HTML comment or a body you
know whatever so yeah that one's that
one's out there I think that one is
actually in the let me check really
quick before I say oh you might need to
update it actually I think because I do
need to update it yeah they moved over
to the new plug-in um the the the
workflows are now have to be in the new
plugin SDK format yeah actually it it is
compatible with that so and and it is in
the um in the uh it is in the even
better workflow library that that even
better ads so if you add even better
plugin to your kaido then it will uh
give you a list of uh workflows that are
just linked back to this GitHub repo
that you can pull request on and I went
ahead and and uh merged in the noaf CL
workl yep I've also I've also got my
color top level and iframe navigations
true I've got that one turned on as well
yeah just extremely helpful like that
will absolutely be a core feature of
kaido soon but in the meantime
definitely use that that to keep track
of where you are in your in your page
refreshes and iframe navigations and
stuff like that so yep absolutely all
right man is that a wrap I think that's
wrap all right sweet peace y'all
peace and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to to ctbb
show/ Discord join the Discord there's
lots of great conversations and chats
going on over there and if you want to
support the show there's the Discord
subscriber tiers which give you access
to master classes amas hack alongs
exclusive scripts and an exclusive chat
Channel with us we'll see you there